<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                         "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>

<chapter id="cb-vmim-images">

  <title>Images</title>
  <chapterinfo>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<firstname>Owen</firstname>
	<surname>Synge</surname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
  </chapterinfo>
  <para>Handling Images and vmimagemanager.</para>
  <para>For &xen; We recommend you setup 2 partitions one for swap and one for your root mount point, the mount point should be then mounted and the image expanded.</para>
  <para>For &kvm; We recommend you setup 1 partitions one the virtual maschines hard drive.</para>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>cd /yourr/mounted/vm/root/directoy/</userinput></screen>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>tar -zxf sl4.5-i386.small.tar.gz</userinput></screen>
  <para>Try this once,</para>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>tar -zxf sl4.5-i386.small.tar.gz</userinput></screen>

  <para>This will create a template file for you where specified in the configuration file.</para>
  <para>You can safely edit this templated file, a new one will not be generated unless the file is missing. I typically.</para>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>xm create -c vm002.yokel.org</userinput></screen>
  <para>For debugging you might like, to edit the configuration file and set this Monitor emulator. It works nicely showing a boot screen,</para>
  <programlisting>sdl=1
vnc=0
vncviewer=0</programlisting>
  <para>Or as I find more convenient occasionally using.</para>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>xm console vm002.yokel.org</userinput></screen>
  <para>Once this vm boots up is successfully,</para>
  <screen>&prompt-root;<userinput>vmimagemanager -b vm002.yokel.org -z -s sl4.5-i386.small.tar.gz</userinput></screen>
  <para>And after some time you should get your first image.</para>
  <para>The recommended setup of images in XEN is one VM with 2 physical devices one for swap and one for data.</para>
  <para>Xen supports only virtualizing the full hard disk drive in fully virtualized mode, and this can be tricky 
    to retrieve as in the case of LVM based distributions like SL4.</para>
  <para><ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/perfect_xen_setup_debian_ubuntu">The Perfect Xen Setup For Debian And Ubuntu</ulink>
  another called <ulink url="http://www.howtoforge.com/perfect_setup_debian_sarge">The Perfect Xen Setup For Debian Sarge</ulink></para>
    
  
</chapter>
