<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                         "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>

<chapter id="setup-xen">

  <title>Setting up on &debian;/&redhat; &xen;</title>
  <chapterinfo>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<firstname>Owen</firstname>
	<surname>Synge</surname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
  </chapterinfo>
  <para>First time users are recommend getting &virtmanager; to work before I trying &vmim;.
  &virtmanager; has a simple GUI for creating &vm;'s which has a dependency upon &libvirt;, further it is
  available in fedora, and debian flavors of line so only a command line away.</para>
  <section id="setup-xen-introduction">
  <title>Dependencies</title>
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>Running Xen kernel (and expected a &vm; has already been booted)</listitem>
      <listitem>Linux platform</listitem>
      <listitem>python</listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <section>
    <title>Tips on setting up &xen;</title>
    <para>
      In the area of Virtualization and the amount of development work going on in this sector,
      Always keep an eye on the latest release of all dependencies versions.
    </para>
    </section>
    <section>
    <title>&lvm; Setup</title>
    <para>
      Which &xen; their are two modes of operation, paravirualization or full virtualization.
      Paravirualization is faster but requires the kernels of the management domain and the
      kernel of the &vm; to pass requests to each other. Paravirualization is a faster technique for
      Virtualization but has the disadvantage in that guests have to use modified kernels.
    </para>
    <para>
      If you are using paravirtualization in Xen you can also export only partitions without the
      &vm; even having a disk, this is recommended if you have a paravirtualizable
      client OS such as Linux, Solaris and maybe Plan9 Kernels. 2 Partitions are recommended
      for parvitualized systems should have swap space for the &vm; Virtual Memory.
      With Linux guests It changes the booting complications but provides an improved performance
      since the hyper visor just gives access control.
    </para>
    <para>
      For exported partition images each slot should have root=/dev/sbird/vm001sys swap=/dev/sbird/vm001swap
      type attributes depending upon your virtulized host name and &lvm; volume group.
    </para>
    <para>
      For exported disks each slot should have its attribute set so &vmim; knows which files system
      to mount from the virtual disks. for a set of library images are loaded on two a set of slots.
      You must decide how to organize this. I recommend buying some fresh large storage half a tera byte,
      attached via SATA or better storage infrastructure.
    </para>
    <para>
      splinting the content 50/50 with space against running images, and create the partitions on demand
      if you don't intend to uses as many images or less static images. If your intending running less .
      &vmim; works for maximum performance of Linux virtualization hence supporting xen. This
      allows the use of para-Virtualization where the best performance exists currently although I have
      not seen comparative data with Solaris containers.
    </para>
    <para>
      At this moment Xen and 3d graphics and advanced graphics interactions has led to data loaded on
      the screen, files system corruption and crashes. For this reason I suggest removing your login
      manager (gdm, kdm , xdm) and shutting down X11 and using ssh to log into your xen server in
      my case an ultra portable laptop with a large USB drive which is a little slow but to work on
      my desktop is just wrong!.
    </para>
    </section>
  </section>
</chapter>
