<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.3//EN"
                         "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.3/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % sharedents SYSTEM "shared-entities.xml" >
%sharedents;
]>

<chapter id="setup-lvm">

  <title>Setting up on LVM</title>
  <chapterinfo>
    <authorgroup>
      <author>
	<firstname>Owen</firstname>
	<surname>Synge</surname>
      </author>
    </authorgroup>
  </chapterinfo>
  <para>Typically any host using &vmim; must work with a large number of partitions.
  With &xen; para virtulization 2 per host for maximum performance, though with &kvm;
  one partition per &vm; slot is enough. With &xen; partition per VM as a root file system and
  one for virtual ram or more commonly known as swap. Unfortunately Linux does not
  recognize more than 15 partitions, on a conventional Intel computer using an MSDOS
  partition table, this limited my experiments with slots to 7 LVM with &xen;.</para>
  <section id="setup-lvm-introduction">
    <title>Running many virtual maschines.</title>
    <para>It seems to get maximum throughput each &vm; should have one core and at least 10Gb
    disk, 512 Mb of RAM. For a typical desktop machine, this leads the RAM and CPU become
    the limiting factor in supporting large numbers of virtual maschines.</para>
    <para>Hard drives are currently large compared to the size of a &vm; image.
    To work around the artificial limit of MSDOS partitions supported by Linux, I recommend LVM.</para>
    <para>LVM provides many features which are appealing to users of &vmim;, these include
    snap shotting, copy on write partitions, and the ability to have an unlimited number of
    partitions within a logical volume group. These features are not integrated into &vmim;
    yet and their is no requirement as yet to use LVM with &vmim;.</para>
    <para>I used <ulink url="http://www.linuxconfig.org/Linux_lvm_-_Logical_Volume_Manager">
    this guide to configuring LVM</ulink> and recommend that all users of &vmim; become
    familiar with the basic usage of &lvm;</para>
  </section>
</chapter>
